Welcome inside the Broncos studio. I'm
your team reporter and host Elisa
Hernandez. Next to our lead writer on
denver broncosc.com, Eric Dala. The
Broncos season has come to an end. We
heard from head coach Shawn Payeyton and
general manager George Payeyton as they
addressed the media at the end of the
season press conferences on a variety of
topics. We're going to talk about our
top takeaways starting with the team's
mentality entering the offseason.
>> Yeah, Lisa, I think obviously it's
helpful when you get to hear from the
team's decision makers following a tough
end of the season. uh the Broncos a
three-point loss the other day in the
AFC Championship game. And I think the
first thing is that George Payton, Shawn
Peyton, they both they both acknowledge
that this is is a painful one. It's a
tough way for the season to end. I think
one thing that stood out to me was that
Shawn Payeyton said, "Listen, in this
business, you're going to suffer these
sorts of tough losses. You're going to
suffer these sorts of gut punches." And
the Broncos have done it before and
they've responded. Whether it was the
loss in Miami a couple of years ago,
whether it was the last second loss to
Kansas City a year ago when the Broncos
responded by winning four in a row and
and surging to the postseason and now
you get another chance in 2026 to
respond to a tough three-point loss when
you're on the doorstep of the Super
Bowl. And Shawn Peyton said you don't
have any other option, right? You can't
not come back ready to go um because
otherwise you'll never get to taste that
success. So that's what stands out first
and foremost. And then it's just it's
about the off season and and how do you
move forward because it's not just
picking up where you left off. It's not
just the next step. You've got to start
from scratch. Sean Payton said, "Listen,
you start the race all over again and
you get your orange slices and you go
back to the starting line and you start
over. But what the team can count on is
one that confidence that you built in
2025, the experience that you got. Um,
and then also from a a more technical
standpoint, the increased salary cap
space you'll have entering this off
seasonason is one of the things that
that makes this an exciting few months
as we gear up for 2026.
>> Yeah. A lot of the talk around was just
the heartbreaking loss of course, but
moving forward and George Payeyton was
asked like, "Do you watch the Super
Bowl?" And he's like, "Yeah." He's like,
he's like, "Right now in this moment,
I'm going to say no. But you watch it
because you love the game." And he said
he told the players that if you envision
yourself there one day, you have to
watch these games. You have to picture
yourself being in that moment. And
that's where you can't be afraid to kind
of go back and and be discouraged to
come back and see yourself once again in
the AFC Championship knowing how quickly
they turned everything around. And
George Payeyton really did credit Shawn
Payeyton and the culture. He's the the
winning culture. He acknowledged, you
know, this team hadn't won in a long
time. And so when you have these
expectations, sometimes you are going to
have that gut punch of h suffering, you
know, a big loss. But they seem really
strong in the foundation that they have
here. and and just the confidence they
have for not only what they accomplish
but going into next season.
>> Yeah, I think there's like you said
there's a good foundation in place. I
think it starts of course with the
quarterback in Boon Knicks, right? And
the way he played this season. We got
kind of a quick injury update on him.
>> Um you know there's no official
timetable. It sounded like at some point
in the offseason he would be back. And
one interesting note that Sean Payton
mentioned on the injury front was that
this was a kind of sooner rather than
later sort of injury that when they went
in and did the surgery, it became clear
this was going to surface at some point.
And so it wasn't um an avoidable sort of
injury, but also doesn't sound like
there's any sort of long-term concern
there. Um, what I will say with Bo is
that it's clear from talking to the guys
on Monday in terms of his teammates and
then also hearing from George Payeyton
just about the confidence that he
inspires in this group and the fact that
>> late in games he's at his best and when
you need him, he's at his best and that
the number one stat in terms of this
team evaluating what they're getting
from the quarterback position is wins.
and George Peyton said it,
>> no quarterback in NFL history has won
more games than Bo Knicks in their first
two seasons. And so, um, as you go into
this off seasonason and you talk about
that foundation and you talk about where
you can add and what you're going to
evaluate, um, I think the fact that, you
know, you've got a quarterback is one of
the things you can hang your hat on and
one of the things that that sets the
tone moving forward and as you look at
free agency and you look at who can we
add, one of the things that that is
going to attract people to come here is
Bon Knicks and and is that quarterback
position. And so, um, from that
standpoint, the Broncos are in really
good shape and it and it gives you
excitement for what 2026 can be.
>> Yeah, Tano Hafunga spoke on that
specifically and he said, "There's a
reason I wore a shirt with his face on
it so that he can feel the confidence
that I have in him so he can see that we
all believe in him and knowing what he's
capable of." George Payton also
mentioned, "There's certain things you
can develop in a quarterback. having
that it factor, having that X factor,
knowing that he said at some point in
the season, even when you're down,
you're like, well, we're going to win
this because Bo Nicks has just shown
that over the years, and you can't teach
that. And so, I think the confidence
that they have and saying that he's been
handling this injury like a pro and and
just the fact that, you know, they're
confident that he will be back. And as
you mentioned, he is a big asset to this
team and he's a lot of the reason why
free agents are going to want to come
here. And on top of so many other things
from ownership to the staff, the medical
staff that helps players get back from
injury. We have talked about this before
the season, saying how the Broncos went
from one of the most injured teams to
one of the most healthy teams because
the in resources that are dumped into
this. And George Payton mentioned that
it's an easy sell when you're talking
about this to free agents.
>> Yeah. And I I think now the the
challenge becomes and and you go into
this offseason, you evaluate your own
roster, how it compares to the rest of
the league, the AFC West. You evaluate
where you need to add. Um you look make
a free agent plan, you make a draft plan
and and it becomes this process. But
even though you have this added salary
cap space now, um you still have to take
a prudent approach as George Payeyton
said, you still have to make good
decisions and you still have to scout
well and and bring the right people in
and and again make those sound decisions
and have another good offseason. And a
year ago, George Payton, Shawn Payton,
they sat there and they said, "Winning
the AFC West is going to be our goal."
And they said that we've got to have a
really good off season to do that. And
and I think they did have a good
offseason. And then obviously they went
and and won the AFC West, got the number
one seed, and now it's time to have
another good offseason. And and George
Payeyton was asked, "Is it Super Bowl or
bus next year?" And he said, "Look,
we're just going to follow the process.
We're going to take this one step at a
time." And he's always had that
approach. But he also did add that
they're going to be aggressive the same
way other teams are going to be
aggressive and that they have to um, you
know, kind of take that step forward.
And so as you go into this offseason, I
think it's exciting to be a Broncos fan
because they have the resources, they
have the opportunity in free agency.
They have the draft picks um to take um
a next step from a roster standpoint,
but then as Sean Payeyton says, the work
has to begin a new cuz you don't just
pick up where you left off. So um an
exciting time for sure as we go into
this offseason. I think the kind of big
theme for me is that there is this
disappointment from the way things
ended, but you have to let it fuel you
and then you have to take what you were
able to accomplish in 2025 and um help
it, you know, have it help you build for
next year.
>> Well, there you have it, Broncos
country. For the latest news and
headlines, make sure you guys visit
denver broncos.com. Stay up to date with
all of the end of the season press
conferences.